(MUSIC PLAYING)
GARY: Ever had
one of those nights
that starts out like
any other, but ends up being
the best night of your life?
GARY:
It was June the 22nd, 1990,
our final day of school.
There was Oliver Chamberlain,
Peter Page, Steven Prince,
Andy Knightley and me.
They called me The King.
Because my name's Gary King.
Ollie was funny, he fancied
himself as a bit of a player,
but really, he was all mouth.
We called him O-Man
because he had a birthmark
on his forehead that looked
like a six.
He loved it.
Pete was the baby
of the group.
He wasn't the kind of kid
we'd usually hang out with,
but he was good for a laugh.
And he was absolutely minted.
Steve was a pretty cool guy.
We jammed together,
chased the girls.
I think he saw us as rivals.
(CHUCKLES) Sweet, really.
And Andy.
Andy was my wingman.
The one guy I could rely
on to back me up.
He loved me,
and I'm not being funny,
but I loved him, too.
There was nothing
we were gonna miss
about school.
Maybe Mr. Shepherd.
He was definitely
one of the good guys.
He used to ask me
what I wanted to
do with my life.
I told him I just wanted
to have a good time.
He thought that was funny.
It wasn't meant to be.
Not that night.
Newton Haven was our hometown.
Our playground, our universe.
And that night
it was the site of
a heroic quest.
The aim? To conquer
The Golden Mile.
Twelve pubs along
a legendary path of
alcoholic indulgence.
There was The First Post,
The Old Familiar,
The Famous Cock,
The Cross Hands,
The Good Companions,
The Trusty Servant,
The Two Headed Dog,
The Mermaid, The Beehive,
The King's Head,
The Hole in the Wall...
All before
reaching our destiny,
The World's End.
We took my car into town.
I called it The Beast
because she was pretty hairy.
And so, our journey
into manhood began.
(RINGS DOORBELL)
We were off.
We didn't waste any time.
We hit pub one
and we hit it hard.
There was drinking,
there was fun,
there was controversy,
there were ladies,
there were shots,
there was drama,
and of course,
there was drinking.
By pub five,
we were feeling invincible
and decided to purchase
some herbal refreshment
from a man we called
The Reverend Green.
Pint six put O-Man out
of commission, so we
carried on without him.
Good thing,
I bumped into his
sister in the next pub,
we went into the disableds
and I bumped into her again.
Sam tagged along for a while,
but then I had to let her go.
I had another date that night
and her name was Amber.
Nine pints in and it was us
against the world.
Things got mental
in The Beehive,
so we repaired to
the bowls club
or as we liked to call it,
The Smokehouse, which is
when it all went fuck up.
Everyone got para and
Pete chucked a whitey,
so we had to bench him.
In the end, we blew
off the last three pubs
and headed for the hills.
I remember sitting up there,
blood on my knuckles,
beer down my shirt,
sick on my shoes,
seeing the orange glow
of a new dawn break
and knowing in my heart,
life would never feel
this good again.
And you know what?
(CHUCKLES)
It never did.
GROUP LEADER: Thank you, Gary.
That was very enlightening.
Would anyone like to
add anything or maybe
challenge Gary?
Are you disappointed?
About what?
That you didn't make it
to The World's End?
(MAN COUGHING)
No.
PASTOR: Just what is it
that you want to do?
PETER FONDA:
We want to be free!
We want to be free to do
what we want to do!
And we want to get loaded.
And we want to have
a good time.
And that's what
we're going to do.
We're going to have
a good time.
We're going to have a party.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
PASTOR: Just what is it
that you want to do?
PETER FONDA: And we want
to get loaded. And we want
to have a good time.
She's a beauty.
Yeah, but she's no Beast.
Hello, Peter.
Jesus! Gary?
The once and future King.
Were you outside my
house this morning?
No.
I could have sworn
I saw you on my street.
I've never been
to Bishop's Gardens.
How you doing, man?
I'm well. You?
Yeah, never better.
How is, uh...
Vanessa?
No. Your wife?
Vanessa.
Yeah. How's she?
She's good.
Have you had sex yet?
We have two children.
Ooh, twice.
Get you, fuck machine.
(LAUGHS)
We haven't changed, have we?
What is he doing here?
It's all right, Dad.
We're fine.
Hi, Mr. P.
So, Gary,
how can I help you?
He looks well.
Are you looking
to buy a car?
Uh... No.
I'm afraid the end is nigh.
What?
The World's End.
What do you mean?
You know what I mean.
One night. Five guys.
Twelve pubs.
Let battle commence.
You want to try
that again?
Yeah, isn't that something
you've always wanted?
Not particularly. No.
Look. Peter.
We didn't make it before,
but this time, we're gonna see
it through to the bitter end.
Or lager end.
We?
Yeah, the whole gang.
Even Andy?
Why wouldn't Andy
be coming?
Well, I thought that
after the accident...
Not an issue. He's in.
What we wanna
know is are you?
I'd have to check
with Vanessa.
Who's Vanessa?
My wife.
Since when have you had to
check with your wife?
Since we got married.
Oh, come on, man,
don't you miss it?
The laughs,
the camaraderie,
the fights,
the hangovers so fierce
it feels like your head
is full of ants.
Maybe the first two.
It begins.
What's your new number?
Same one I've had
for 10 years.
Yeah. What's that one?
This entire row here, they'll
all have dormer windows
above the front elevation.
Who's the helmet
without an helmet?
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
That's Gary King.
Knock, knock.
What are you
doing here, Gary?
You're supposed to say,
"Who's there?"
I can see who's there.
It's you.
(CHUCKLES) I like what
you've done with the place.
Bit draughty.
How's Selina?
We divorced 10 years ago.
Yeah, I know,
just wondered
how she was.
She's doing very well,
apparently.
Have you got anyone
else on the go?
Yeah, I do, as it happens.
She's a fitness instructor.
Twenty-six.
Pedophile. I'm kidding.
I'd love to meet her sometime.
No. Why are you here?
Haven't you heard?
We're getting the band
back together.
I'm not your
bass player anymore.
No, I mean
we're getting the boys
back together.
We can get the band
back together as well
if you want.
No, we can't.
You sold my guitar
to buy drugs.
I've always wondered,
what's that thing over
the door called?
That's a lintel.
So, the plan is,
we're going to go
back to Newton Haven,
we are gonna do
The Golden Mile
and this time,
we are gonna make it
to The World's End.
Everybody's in.
What, even Andy?
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, you better
believe it, big balls.
Andy is going
drinking with you?
With us.
Think about it,
go back to the old town,
sink a few pints...
Twelve pints.
Yeah.
Twelve pints is insane.
(CHUCKLES) I know!
What is this
all about, Gary?
It's about closure,
you know.
Why should getting
older affect something as
important as friendship?
A lot's changed
since then, Oliver.
Right.
This is our chance
to take stock.
A stock take?
You make it sound so much fun.
Come on, O-Man.
Isn't that something
you'd like?
What I'd really like is
for you to take your
DMs off the sofa.
Look. If you're worried
about me, don't be.
All right?
I'm here to tell you
that Gary King is back
on the horse.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're back on the horse?
No, I mean
I'm back on the bike.
What is bike?
What do you mean?
What is bike slang for?
Bicycle.
I'm lost.
Don't be.
Okay.
Listen.
This is our chance
to finally finish
what we started.
Come on, man,
it'll be fucking mental!
I think we're all done.
So...
How do you like
the property?
Yeah. It's amazing.
Amazing location.
Fantastic.
Fantastic aspects.
It's just...
It's just a little bit out
of our price range.
He'll knock some off for you.
What's it down for?
1.2 million.
Fuck off!
(SIGHS)
You have my card.
Gary, WTF?
It's good to see you,
too, O-Man.
Please don't call me O-Man.
Sure.
Hey, how's your sister?
She's fine.
She talk about me?
No.
So, Friday, we'll all
go down together.
Make a road trip of it,
I'll drive.
Don't think I can.
I think I've got
a doctor's appointment.
Yeah, you do.
With Dr. Ink!
You know, Dr. Ink?
Yeah. "Drink." I get it.
Come on.
It wouldn't be the same
without the O-Man.
Jesus.
You can see the guys,
see how they're doing.
Tell them how you're doing.
You never know,
you might make it
to the end this time.
And Andy's
definitely coming?
Yeah.
Andy Knightley?
Totes.
And you convinced him how?
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Mr. Knightley.
Felicity.
You have a friend
here to see you.
No, I don't.
(CHUCKLES)
This is a bit grown up,
isn't it?
Yup.
Saw the boys the other day.
Mmm-hmm.
O-Man, Stevie-Baby,
the Petertron.
Yeah, I remember the names of
our childhood friends, Gary.
We had ourselves
a little idea.
Did you now?
Yeah.
We're going to go
back to Newton Haven.
Why?
For some
unfinished business.
That's a joke, right?
Five guys. Twelve pubs.
Fifty pints.
Sixty pints.
(LAUGHS)
Steady on,
you fucking alky.
I haven't had a drink
for 16 years, Gary.
You must be thirsty then.
(SIGHS)
We can go back, see the guys,
chew the fat, it'll be just
like it always was,
except this time we're
going to finish this thing
once and for all.
You have a very
selective memory, Gary.
Thanks.
You remember
the Friday nights.
I remember the
Monday mornings.
Yeah, that's why
we're going back
on a Friday.
(SIGHS)
Why do you think none of us
live in Newton Haven anymore?
I don't know.
Because it's a black hole.
It's boring.
It always was
and it always will be.
It's only boring
because we're not there.
It's pointless
arguing with you.
Exactly. So come.
I'm picking everybody up from
High Wycombe station, Friday,
3:00 sharp.
No, Gary.
Oh, God, why?
Have you got to check
with your missus?
No, actually,
I don't have to check
with my missus.
What are you doing?
I'm showing you the door.
Is it a door?
It doesn't have a lintel.
And it's glass.
So is it a window
or is it a door?
Maybe it's a windoor.
(CHUCKLES) You can have that.
Please leave, Gary.
(SIGHS)
All right. All right.
£600, wasn't it?
Oh, um, I thought
you should know.
What?
Mum died.
When?
Couple of weeks ago.
The big cancer.
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
She just always really
liked you, you know.
Got me thinking
about the old days.
Particularly that night,
you know, because
we were so happy.
And, you know,
I love the boys
like brothers,
but when all's said and done,
you're the best friend
I ever had.
It was good to
see you, mate.
Pete?
Steven. Thank God.
I had a horrible feeling
I was going to be
the only one here.
I reckon that's not
the last horrible feeling
you're gonna have today, mate.
This can't be happening.
Can it?
You said it.
What the hell
are we doing here?
What we always did.
Follow Gary King
into almost certain
oblivion.
Hello, Steven.
You all right, mate?
Pete. Hi, mate.
Didn't we decide to stop
calling him Fearless Leader
somewhere around 1992?
Old habits die hard.
They'll be putting that
on Gary's tombstone.
No, they won't.
You know he'll outlive us all.
That'd be funny
if it wasn't true.
Hang on a sec.
What?
I'm just trying to decide
which of us is the biggest
idiot for coming.
(WHISTLING)
Maybe he had
an accident.
Oh, sorry, Andy.
Sorry.
No, no, no.
It's fine.
I think Gary having
an accident
would actually be the
best outcome for all of us,
including Gary.
(HORN HONKING)
Unbelievable.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(LAUGHS)
Oh, yes.
Look at these cunts.
You're late.
No, I'm not.
Yeah, you are.
You said 3:00.
It's almost 4:00.
Yeah, 3 for 4.
You know your problem, Gary?
You're never wrong.
How is that a problem?
I can't believe
you bought another
Granada Mark II.
What do you mean?
This looks exactly like
the car I sold you in 1989.
This is the car
you sold me in 1989.
Best 300 quid I ever spent.
This is The Beast?
Yeah.
Pretty much.
I mean, she's had
a bit of work done.
I had to replace the brakes,
suspension, exhaust, seats,
wheels,
paneling, carburetor,
manifold, the whole engine,
really, mirrors, headlamps.
Other than that,
she's the same old motor.
You could almost
say an antique.
Well, then let's
get this antique
on the roadshow.
(BELLS TOLLING)
Come on, you bellends.
We're going to be late.
And we're back.
Just like the Five Musketeers.
Three Musketeers,
isn't it?
Four if you count
D'Artagnan.
Well, nobody knows how many
there were, really, do they,
Pete?
I mean,
history's a sketchbook.
You do know that
The Three Musketeers
is a fiction, right?
Written by Alexandre Dumas?
A lot of people are saying
that about the Bible these
days.
What, that it was written
by Alexandre Dumas?
(CHUCKLES)
Don't be daft, Steve,
it was written by Jesus.
Oh.
Anyway, five sounds
much better.
I think they missed a trick
only having three.
'Cause you'd have five,
then two could've died and
they'd still have three left.
Are we there yet?
Let's do this!
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC PLAYING OVER STEREO)
(SINGING)
Soup Dragons!
I remember this one.
I put this on a tape
for you, didn't I?
Yeah, this is it.
This is the tape?
Yeah, yeah! Look, look.
Where did you find it?
It was in the tape player.
Oh, look. Is anyone hungry?
(GROANS)
I need a piss actually.
(HORNS HONKING)
This is a long piss.
If it is a piss.
Might be a little...
Poo.
How is that a poo?
Still work for your
old man, Pete?
Yeah. I'm a partner now.
You?
Yeah, started
my own firm in '98.
Got bought out in '05.
I'm happier, though.
It's less stress.
Ollie?
Property.
I co-manage
a boutique estate agency
in North London.
Very competitive.
Is it family law
you're in, Andy?
Corporate.
Does anyone know
what Gary's doing?
He's playing
Need For Speed.
Over there.
Come on, come on,
come on!
He hasn't changed, has he?
I don't know.
He did finally pay
me back that £600.
Really?
He borrowed £200 off me.
And me.
ANDY: I can't believe it.
I can't believe you'd do that!
Oh! Of course I can.
It's just robbing
Peter to pay Paul.
No, I borrowed it
from Peter to pay you.
I still owe Paul. (LAUGHS)
Oh, shit.
Newton Haven.
Take a moment to look upon it
in its original colors, boys,
for tonight we paint it red.
(GARY WHOOPING)
(SIREN WAILING)
Oh, no, no, no. Shit.
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Fuck, fuck.
Oh, no, it's okay,
I did it all in the services.
(SNIFFLES)
(KNOCKS)
Know why I pulled
you over, sir?
Was the music too loud?
Your left brake light
is faulty.
Oh! (CHUCKLES)
The old brake lights!
So called because they're
always breaking.
I'll get that sorted out,
Officer.
Can I see your license, sir?
Yup.
Ah!
You know what?
It's in my wallet.
And I left that
at the bloody gym!
Any other form
of identification?
No, it's all in my sports bag.
That's bloody typical,
isn't it? Um...
I'll give you my name
and address, you can run
me through the old system.
Go on then.
It's Peter Page.
48 Bishop's Gardens,
London, N2 T1 2.
Jesus, Gary! WTF?
Why did you give
him my name?
I'm not gonna give
him my name, am I?
Suppose I get done
by the police?
You won't get done
by the police.
Gary, he will check
the number plate
against his name!
I know.
Why do you think
I gave him Pete's name?
Jesus Christ, Gary,
I own a car showroom.
I am a junior partner.
This is...
(SQUABBLING)
Just trust me.
So, Mr. Page,
what brings you
to Newton Haven?
Well, we're all from here.
We're just back to see
the sights.
Have a crack at
the old Golden Mile.
Might get a bit messy.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, you make sure
you get that brake light
fixed
and you might want to do
an emissions test, too.
Oh, and, Peter.
Don't make too much mess.
(LAUGHS)
We won't!
Hmm.
(WHISPERS)
I don't understand.
It's simple, Pete.
The car's still
registered to you,
it has been since 1989.
But I've moved
three times since then.
I know, I changed
the log book.
Where do you think
all those points came from?
Jesus. You guys need to relax.
(GARY SHOUTING)
ANDY:
Do you know how much
trouble you could get into?
GARY: Do you know
how much trouble
I'm already in?
What's that
supposed to mean?
Hey. What the hell is this?
Why are we even here?
We are here to
get annihilated.
(RINGS BELL)
Have you got any plans
for dinner at all?
Tonight, we will be
partaking of a liquid
repast
as we wend our way
up The Golden Mile.
Commencing with
an inaugural tankard
at The First Post,
then onto The Old Familiar,
The Famous Cock,
The Cross Hands,
The Good Companions,
The Trusty Servant,
The Two Headed Dog,
The Mermaid, The Beehive,
The King's Head
and The Hole in the Wall
for a measure of the same.
All before the last
bittersweet pint in that
most fateful terminus,
The World's End.
Leave a light on,
good lady,
for though we may return
with a twinkle in our eyes,
we will, in truth,
be blind drunk.
(ALTERNATIVE ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(RINGS DOORBELL)
Come on!
Until 1840...
Fucking hell.
...this building was
the site of Newton Haven's
first post office.
Until an enterprising
business fellow decided that
far from befitting
the sending and
receiving of mail
it was perhaps
better suited
as a humble taproom
where a weary traveler
might get twatted.
(CHUCKLES) Come on.
Ah! (CHUCKLES)
It's like déjà vu.
(TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
I don't remember this at all.
Has it been refurbished?
Been bought by a chain,
hasn't it?
Part of that nationwide
initiative to rob
small, charming pubs
of any discernible character.
Starbucking, man.
It's happening everywhere.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Can't take away
that smell, though.
I'm sure they tried.
Good evening, Raymondo.
The prodigal sons return.
Eh?
Who's on the
guest list tonight?
Come again?
The guest ales.
We, sir, are doing
The Golden Mile
and you have
the honor of drawing
first blood.
What do you recommend?
There's one.
Crowning Glory.
Rather fitting.
How's that?
I'm Gary King.
What?
So tell me more.
About what?
Crowning Glory.
Is it nutty? Is it foamy?
Is it hoppy?
Does it have a surprisingly
fruity note which lingers
on the tongue?
Hmm. It's beer.
Hmm.
We'll have five
of those, please.
No. Sorry.
Can we have four of those
and a tap water, please?
What?
(ANDY GULPING)
I don't believe this,
a man of your
legendary prowess
drinking fucking rain.
It's like seeing a lion
eating some hummus.
That doesn't make any sense.
I know it doesn't
make any sense.
You seriously have a problem
with me not drinking,
after what happened?
I don't, but King Arthur does!
Oh, this'll be good.
What's King Arthur
got to do with it?
Do you honestly think
that King Arthur came back
from the Battle of Hastings,
fucking rocked up
at Arthur's Castle...
Camelot.
...walked up to the bar
and went,
"Hello.
Could I have a tap water?"
No, because they didn't
have running water
in Arthurian times.
Exactly.
He would have had a mead.
The King Arthur of beers.
And I'm less of a man
because I choose to
drink water?
Well, it's a bit
"ooh ducky", innit?
That's not very PC, Gary.
Get out of the '90s, Pete.
There's nothing "ooh ducky"
about being teetotal,
about walking into a pub
after a rugby match
and ordering a tap water at
a bar packed full of big ugly
bastards wearing warpaint.
That, my friend,
takes confidence, yeah?
I'm talking balls.
(CHUCKLES)
You said it, poof.
I don't know if you're aware
of this, Gary, but we are not
teenagers anymore.
And God forbid
you ever have children,
because if...
I might have kids.
Then you had better
be ready to take
responsibility...
No. I mean I might have kids.
You remember
Karen Eggerton,
who I fucked?
She was two weeks late
when her parents emigrated
to Normandy.
I never heard from her again.
She might have had a baby.
Imagine that? A French kid.
It's pointless arguing
with you.
To kids.
Wherever they may be.
Kids.
Drink up. Let's Boo-Boo.
"Boo-Boo".
What is that?
You remember,
"Let's Boo-Boo."
You know, from
Mr. Shepherd's classroom,
it said on the wall,
"Exit, pursued by a bear,"
you know, from that
Shakespeare play?
A Winter's Tale.
Yeah. What was it called?
That's it.
And if we needed to make
a quick getaway, we'd say,
"Exit, pursued by a bear,"
and then it was,
"Exit, pursued by Yogi Bear,"
and then it was just,
"Let's Yogi and Boo-Boo,"
and then, "Let's Boo-Boo."
So you're saying
we should go?
Yeah. It's shit here, innit?
GARY: Ah!
The Old Familiar.
Now this is a pub.
(LAUGHS) Yes.
This is more like it.
(TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
Like déjà vu.
David, my man,
have you heard the news?
Gary King is back in town.
Who's he?
(BURPS)
How was the
funeral, Gary?
Your mum's funeral?
It's difficult to
put into words.
But if I had to choose
three, I would say,
"Really, really sad."
Oh, no, that's two,
isn't it?
How about,
"Really, very sad"?
It's a shame, (SIGHS)
she was a good woman.
I really liked your mum.
(CHUCKLES)
Me, too, mate. Me, too.
Hello.
Hello, mate.
Are you here?
Yeah, I've been here for ages.
What are you talking about?
You get lost on the
ring road again?
This is Newton Haven.
What time are you
meeting The Twins?
Twins?
We're all at The Old Familiar.
Come by if you want.
Yeah, he is. Okay.
See you soon.
Who was that, O-Man?
Don't call me O-Man, Gary.
If you must know it was Sam.
Sam's here?
Is there a fucking
echo in here?
Yes, Sam's here.
She's down from Manchester.
We're driving to Mum's
tomorrow.
What, and she's coming here?
Calm down, Steve,
I saw her first.
Jesus Christ, not this again.
Are you fucking kidding me?
I saw her first.
You really have
a selective memory,
don't you?
Somebody else
was saying that.
Me.
No. I would have
remembered.
I told you I had
a thing about Sam
and you proceeded to try
and get in her pants
at every opportunity.
Guys, please.
You only liked her
after you found out
I liked her!
That's right,
because you did
the school play.
Cabaret.
Because she was in it.
And she wore those
fishnet stockings and you
got a big boner on stage.
(LAUGHING)
Jesus Christ.
Doesn't matter anyway,
she always had a massive
wide on for Adrian Keane.
I hated that prick.
Can we not talk about
my sister in relation to,
A, massive wide ons,
B, Steven's erect penis?
All right.
Is she still fit, though?
I'm not answering that.
Is she, though?
Am I what?
Fit.
Hello, Sam.
Steven? You've grown,
haven't you?
Yeah, sideways.
You look fantastic.
Steroids.
Andy, long time.
Hi, Pete.
Hi, Sam.
All right, big brother?
Gary.
Willkommen. Bienvenue.
Welcome.
Sam. Would you like a drink?
Hey, Steve.
She's just got here.
Come on.
Sam. Would you like a drink?
I'll have a vodka tonic,
thanks, Steven.
Sure.
I'm just going to
nip to the loo.
Cool.
(CHUCKLES)
Nature calls.
What are you doing?
I'm going to the toilet.
Well, then, so am I.
Gary! You are
out of your mind!
What are you talking about?
You gave me the sign.
What sign?
You went to the toilet.
Gary, are you serious?
I haven't seen you
in 20 years.
Do you really think I'm
going to have sex with you
in the ladies' toilet?
Well, the disableds
is out of order.
Gary. What happened?
I don't know,
maybe one of them put too many
paper towels down the toilet.
I mean, we don't know
what they are thinking,
really, do we?
No. What happened to you?
Nothing.
Nothing happened to me.
I'm the same old Gary.
No shit.
Huh!
So, do you wanna?
Oliver. I'll see you later.
You're going?
I thought you weren't
meeting The Twins for
another half hour?
I'm not. Oh, yeah.
I believe this is yours.
(CHUCKLES)
"Out of order."
It's a private joke.
I don't want to know.
What is that?
OLIVER: Modern art.
PETER: It's a memorial,
isn't it?
Yeah. To modern art.
Hey, guys, do you
know what time it is?
It's not even 6:00.
Wrong! It's high time
we got onto The Cock!
Whoo-hoo!
Let's go.
Come on.
(LAUGHING)
When you're ready, mate.
Oh, shit.
Look who it is.
Basil. Mad Basil!
Do you remember?
We used to come in here
and listen to him talk about
fucking UFOs and lizard people
and underwater Nazis.
OLIVER:
Didn't he spout some bullshit
about the Bermuda Triangle
actually being a square?
No, he said it was two
isosceles triangles
forming a rhombus.
He was your best mate,
wasn't he, Steve?
No, he wasn't my
best mate, Gary.
He was a lonely, old guy
and I felt a bit sorry
for him.
That's right. Basil!
Maybe we're not
the local legends
you think we are.
Gary King?
Speak for yourself, mate.
You're barred.
I cannot fucking believe this.
This is ridiculous.
Believe me, Gary,
it's not worth it.
Have two in the next one.
Have them all in the next one,
for all I care.
We've got to have one
in every pub otherwise
the whole thing's fucked.
I'd say it was fairly
fucked already, mate.
Great.
How much more of this
do we have to endure?
That was three.
There's nine more.
Oh, good.
Fuck that.
I need to eat something.
We can get some food
in the next pub.
As long as it's
reasonably healthy.
This is Newton Haven.
Hardly the heart of the
organic revolution.
I doubt it's the
heart of anything.
My wife wanted us to go
organic, problem is,
I kinda like eating shit.
The next pub does shit!
Keep up!
(JEERING)
STEVEN: Oh, yeah.
I remember this one.
GARY: We had New Year's
in here, didn't we?
PETER: '89 into '90.
OLIVER:
Isn't that when you slept
on the pool table, Andy?
Yeah. I believe it was.
OLIVER: For six hours.
Six hours.
Thank you for reminding me.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Do you remember
when you woke up,
we said you'd been
asleep for a year
and that it was 1991
and you freaked out
and punched a clock?
(ALL LAUGHING)
That was a great night.
Didn't you manage to get off
with Erika Leekes, Peter?
Yes, I did.
Something of a personal
triumph, if I say so myself.
She of the
Marmalade Sandwich fame?
Marmalade Sandwich...
The very same.
Erika Leekes, Tracy Benson,
Becky Salt.
Two blondes and a redhead
in the middle.
The Marmalade Sandwich.
Becky Salt. Fucking hell.
Wonder what
they're doing now.
Why don't you ask them?
What do you mean?
I mean, sitting at that table
over there are two blondes
and a redhead in the middle.
Shut the fuck up.
I'd say that's Erika Leekes
on the left, Tracy Benson
on the right,
and by process of elimination,
there's Becky Salt in the
middle.
That's the Marmalade Sandwich
all growed up.
That is very spooky.
(LAUGHING)
We should get them over.
No.
Leave the past where it is.
It's bad enough
having to look at
your old, ugly mugs.
You make it sound like
we're fucking ancient.
We haven't changed that much.
I mean, sure, Steve's
let himself go a bit.
What?
Pete's got the same haircut
and Oliver has still got
his mark of the devil.
No, he hasn't.
It's called
laser surgery, Gary.
It's a small price to pay
for not being called
fucking O-Man.
That works for
Sisters Of Mercy
tattoos as well.
I still like the
Sisters Of Mercy.
Well, good job,
or you'd never go swimming.
I'm lost.
Don't be.
Well, I for one,
think it's nice to see
the old faces again.
Cheers, mate.
Excuse me? This taken?
Is this seat taken?
Have it, mate.
Thanks.
Wasn't that...
Shane Hawkins.
Hey, didn't he...
Yes, he did.
Hang on.
What happened with
Shane Hawkins again?
I'd rather not bring
it all up again,
if that's okay.
Hey, man. Listen, Pete.
Bottling up past trauma
can lead to
inadequate coping strategies
in later life, apparently.
I don't know, I mean,
it's not even about the
past, you know.
It's not about the fact
that he bullied me,
that he made me
miss more school days
than chicken pox.
It's not even that he forced
me to spend entire lessons
hiding in a toilet cubicle,
or that he punched me so hard
he dislodged my eyeball.
And it's not even that
he ruined a large portion
of my childhood.
No, it's the fact
that just then,
he didn't recognize me.
He looked straight through me
like it all meant nothing.
That probably sounds weird,
doesn't it?
Shots!
S-H-O-T-S. Shots.
What are you doing, Gary?
I thought it was obvious.
Shots.
Firstly, Peter was talking
about something
which clearly
made him feel very
uncomfortable.
It's all right, Andy.
No, Peter, it's not all right.
Secondly, 12 pints is more
than enough, and thirdly,
I don't fucking drink!
But shots don't count,
do they?
You said you wanted
to catch up and chew the fat.
I think you just
wanted to drink it.
We're not here
as your friends.
We're just your
fucking enablers.
Enablers.
That's a funny word,
isn't it? "Enabler."
Gary King And The Enablers.
That's a good name
for a band, Steve.
Write that down.
Don't do a Gary, Gary.
Oh, is that
a thing now, is it?
It's always been a thing.
You don't need us to
help you get fucked up,
you've done a perfectly
good job so far on your own.
I'm gonna go and see
if there's a bus back
to London
if anyone wants to
come with me.
You can't go. This is special.
This is our anniversary.
It's not the
anniversary, Gary.
We did this in June.
It's October.
Yeah, but it's the anniversary
of the year, isn't it?
Every year is the
anniversary of a year!
It's just not the
same anymore, Gary,
and it's not that
the town's changed,
we have changed.
Yeah, well, you can't go,
'cause the buses are finished.
Then I'm gonna go
back to the B&B.
You coming?
I could do with
an early one actually.
I should probably go
and find Sam.
Yeah, I'm gonna go
and find Sam with Oliver.
That's settled then, yeah?
You know what I think?
I think you're jealous.
Yeah, you've got your houses
and your cars and your wives
and your job security.
But you don't have
what I have. Freedom.
You're all slaves
and I'm free to do
what I want any old time.
And this is what you want?
You should grow up, mate.
Join society.
Yeah, but Mum died.
And we're all very sorry,
but now it's time to go home.
I thought we were home.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
I can't help feeling
sorry for him.
(MOBILE VIBRATING)
Don't.
(FLUSHING)
Oh! Fuck! Piss!
Careful, the floor's
a bit pissy.
Wasn't me.
That was me.
(CHUCKLES)
Did that back in '90.
1990.
Punched the shit
out of the wall. (LAUGHS)
I don't know why.
Seemed important
at the time.
You guys look like
you're having a good night,
though.
I'm doing
The Golden Mile tonight.
You want to tag along?
We'll be like
The Six Musketeers.
(ZIPS UP)
I said we're doing
The Golden Mile.
You think you're so cool,
don't you?
Huh?
But we were cooler.
We owned this town.
We paved the
way for you lot.
Blazed a trail.
Hey! Look at me
when I'm talking
to you!
Please don't.
Don't what?
You don't want
to do that.
(SCOFFS) Don't I?
(SCREAMS)
(GARY PANTING)
What?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
You need to explain
this right now!
Andy, this kid
just attacked me.
Don't you dare
change the subject!
He smashed my head
in the mirror.
You know who
I just spoke to?
Your mum!
And not from the afterlife.
From fucking Bournemouth.
Is that real?
She says she hasn't
spoken to you
for eight months.
Andy...
His head just came off!
No, Gary, you are not gonna
wriggle out of it this time.
(ALL SCREAMING)
WTF!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
There's someone in here.
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
Andy, did you see...
(ALL GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
WTF, Gary. WTF.
What the fuck
does "WTF" mean?
What the fuck?
Oh, yeah.
This can't be happening.
Can it?
(PANTING)
You said it, mate.
I can't believe it.
I know, mate.
I can't believe
you lied about
your mum!
That was a white lie!
How is that a white lie?
She's not dead, is she?
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Wait, wait, wait!
Where are you going?
To get help.
No, don't do that!
What, don't get help?
We don't know
how far this goes.
Wait, who are you calling?
Vanessa.
Who's Vanessa?
My wife.
Why are you calling your wife?
Because she's my wife.
You just said
we don't know
how far this goes.
I was just thinking
about the pub.
Oh, well, there's a surprise.
I can't get through.
Can you get through to Sam?
I've got full bars and
I'm not getting through.
OPERATOR: I'm sorry,
your call cannot be
connected at this time.
Must be the network.
Holy shit.
This is all connected.
This explains why
everything's gone fuck up.
Everybody's been replaced
by one of these.
That's why no one
recognized us, Basil,
Dave, Raymondo.
I thought it was weird.
Shane Hawkins.
Exactly. It's not
us that's changed,
it's the town.
I'm right, aren't I, Andy?
Andy, aren't I right?
You're never wrong.
No, whatever the fuck's
happening, we can't stay
in the gents forever.
Ten people have entered
this toilet in the last
five minutes
and not a single one
has come back out again.
That's going to
look suspicious.
(GASPS) Gay loving.
And that's worse
than five dismembered bodies?
This is Newton Haven.
(SIGHS)
(ALL PANTING)
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
How's it looking?
Normal. Very normal.
I don't like it.
What do we do?
Let's finish our drinks.
I say we neck these
and get the fuck
out of here.
To London?
To The Trusty Servant.
Are you fucking kidding?
Oh, yeah.
It's The Good Companions next.
I always mix those two up.
Are you saying
we move on to
the next pub?
We should get in The Beast
and head back to London!
My brake light is broken.
So don't use the brakes!
I'm way over the limit.
When has that ever
stopped you?
I don't want to put
any more points on
Pete's license.
Andy can drive,
he's teetotal!
(GROANS)
Ah!
That's settles it then.
The last thing we need to do
is get pulled over by the
police.
A, we're all drunk,
B, they might be in on it
and, C, we've got blood
on our hands.
It's more like ink.
We've got ink
on our hands.
So, has it got
messy yet?
What?
What are you,
five pubs in?
Four.
Oh, not even halfway.
Plenty more fun to be had.
Enjoy your night, Peter.
Thank you.
Sorry.
The way I see it,
we've told everybody we were
doing The Golden Mile.
You did.
If we suddenly jump
in The Beast now and
head for the hills,
they're gonna know
that we know,
but if we keep doing
what we're doing and
going where we're going,
then they're not gonna know.
Know what?
That we know.
I suggest we finish what
we started and leave quietly
in the morning.
Wait.
You're really suggesting...
We finish The Golden Mile.
It's pointless
arguing with him.
Drink up. Let's Boo-Boo.
GARY: We're just five friends
on a night out,
having a good time.
(CLASSIC ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL EXHALE)
Drinking.
Ah!
Beer.
Pubs.
(BURPS)
Shall we?
PETER: I feel a little
uncomfortable drinking
this much.
GARY: It's like Dutch
courage, isn't it?
You know, when the English
soldiers used to drink
Dutch gin before battle
to give them super strength.
You know, I thought
that was to numb the
sense of impending doom.
Exactly.
We're just five
friends on a night out,
having a good time.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I need the toilet.
Go on then.
You've earned it.
Huh?
You're doing really
good, Oliver.
(SIGHS)
He didn't make it
this far last time.
I'm proud of him.
You're enjoying this,
aren't you?
Yeah, five guys
on a night out,
having a great time.
Pretending to have
a great time.
Are you pretending?
If we get out of here alive,
I'm going to kill you.
We're still
in the dark, Gary.
Yeah, our families
could be in danger
for all we know.
I know, my mum could be dead.
For reals this time.
Hey, why don't we
just ask somebody?
Who?
The Reverend Green.
Come on.
Wait.
What the fuck
are you doing?
I'm going to go and
have a little chat with
The Reverend Green.
You're going to buy drugs?
I am going to go over there
and subtly check if that is
The Reverend Green
and if it is, I can ask him
what's going on,
and possibly buy some drugs.
But what if he's one of them?
No, me and The Reverend
had a highly sophisticated
code
when discussing
the purchase of
herbal narcotics.
If he doesn't understand me,
it means he's one of them
and I will simply walk away.
Ah!
Have you got any drugs?
I don't do that
anymore, Gary.
Do what?
That.
That why you're
in a suit, is it?
'Cause drug dealing is
not good enough for you?
There are no
drug dealers
anymore, Gary.
I've got a proper job
in a proper office.
You had a proper office.
That was the gents' toilets.
Nothing wrong with doing
your business in the toilet.
Look, a lot has changed
since you have left.
I know.
How much do you know?
A little.
How much is a little?
The town has been taken over
by robots full of blue stuff.
Shh. Keep your voice down.
You don't even know
what you're talking about.
Tell us then.
Well, they're not robots.
Do you even know
what robot means?
Course I do. It's like,
"Hello, I am a robot."
It means "slave"
and believe me,
they are not slaves.
Are you their prisoner?
No, I am very happy.
(SCOFFS)
Tell your face.
Hey! What's going on?
The town's been invaded
by robots who aren't robots
and The Rev's their prisoner.
I am not.
We're leaving first thing.
We can get you out of here.
I'm not going.
It's not what you think.
This is for all our benefit.
You've said too much, Trevor.
Yeah, put a cork
in it, Trevor.
I'm just trying to help.
It's not your place to help.
They will have
everything in hand.
Are you guys robots?
Well, the word robot
actually comes from
an old Czech word...
...robotnik...
...meaning slave.
And we are not slaves.
We are very, very happy.
And not robots.
Oh, my God,
are these guys robots?
Shut up about robots!
I say we shut up
about everything!
(PHONE RINGING)
(INDISTINCT)
Trevor.
It's your supervisor.
Hello, Trevor.
Hello, sir.
But...
I understand.
Thanks a bunch.
What did I miss?
Your friends
trying to help.
We don't need
your help.
Well, what should we do?
I suggest you get
on your way.
I think we should
do what he says.
Okay.
(GARY CHATTERING)
GARY: Here we go.
Come on!
Gary.
Gary!
Let's just get in and
out of this one, yeah?
No more making new friends.
Gentlemen!
The prodigal sons return!
What will it be,
one of our guest
ales perchance?
Might I recommend
five pints of Crowning Glory?
Rather fitting,
wouldn't you say, Gary?
What? Sorry. What?
It's a delightful brew.
Hoppy, nutty, foamy.
Does it have a surprisingly
fruity note that lingers on
the tongue?
You're obviously
a connoisseur.
(LAUGHS)
Then you'll already
know that it's a rare treat
for rogues, reverends, royalty
and all good folks between.
Five of those, please.
Welcome home, boys.
I don't remember him
being that friendly.
He's obviously
one of them.
How can he be?
He remembered me.
We don't know
what they remember.
OLIVER: Maybe they
have selective memories.
Yeah, like what's his name?
Me.
Maybe he's one of the others.
Like The Reverend.
It is very hard
to tell, isn't it?
Yeah, I mean,
is he one of them
or is he one of them?
Wait, wait, which ones
are the thems again?
Well, they're both thems,
aren't they?
But there's two ways
of saying it.
Is he one of them or
is he one of them?
We need different terms.
One for the people who aren't
robots and one for the robots
who aren't robots.
All right, we need to be
able to differentiate between
them, them and us.
Yeah, I think the pronouns
are really confusing.
ALL: Yes.
I don't even know
what a pronoun is.
It's a word
that can function
by itself as a noun
which refers to something
else in the discourse.
I don't get it.
You just used one.
Did I?
Yeah. "It" is a pronoun.
What is?
It.
Is it?
Christ.
Look, we just need
a fucking word
so we can identify who's who.
He's a blank, she's a blank,
those two people are
definitely blanks.
Sam.
I got this, Steve.
All right, Sam?
Oh, crumbs.
How's your night going?
(SIGHS)
Good. Sort of.
What do you mean
"sort of"?
Well, it's weird, isn't it?
You come back
and everything's the same,
but sort of different.
Different how?
Just weird.
How weird?
What are you getting at, Gary?
Come with me.
Fuck's sake, Gary,
take a hint.
It's all right,
I'm not trying to
have sex with you.
Why are we in the
disabled toilets then?
There's something
I need to tell you
right now,
unless you do
want to have sex,
in which case
I'll tell you afterwards.
Tell me right now.
Have you noticed anything
creepy about The Twins
apart from the fact
that they're twins?
Just because they're twins
doesn't automatically make
them creepy.
It does a little bit.
You had sex with them.
A, I did not,
and, B, how did you
know about that?
A, it's a small town,
B, I'm not stupid and,
C, they told me.
Right. Well, I did once,
but I was wasted,
which was creepy
because it was like
there was four of them.
I am not proud of it.
I am a bit.
Is this what you
wanted to tell me?
No, this is...
(SAM SLAPS)
(GARY SCREAMS)
Are you okay, Sam?
I need a cigarette.
Nobots?
How about Fauxbots?
I think we should get away
from the whole robots thing.
Steven?
What's he up to?
Oh, don't worry, he's probably
just trying to fuck Oliver's
sister.
Andy.
Oh, my God,
that man is full of shit.
I know that's not
a surprise to you.
What did he say, Sam?
He said that Newton Haven
has been taken over by
robots full of blue stuff
and if we don't do
what they say, they will
make us their prisoners.
Did you believe him?
No, of course not.
What?
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
See?
Come on, Sam.
You know better than
to believe Gary King.
Oh, crumbs.
Sam!
(MUFFLED) God!
You creepy bitches, get off!
(GRUNTING)
Chuck us a ciggie.
Oh.
Gary, what's happening?
I told you in the disableds.
Oh, yes, you did.
We should get inside, eh?
Otherwise people
are going to ask what
the hell's going on.
What the hell's going on?
Steve, I got this.
Got what?
Sam, he's not good
enough for you.
What?
We've been through
some crazy shit tonight
and it's really put things
in perspective for me,
and if everything is as fucked
up as it seems, then there's
something I need to tell you.
You might think this is
because I've had seven pints,
but it's not.
It's not.
I'm in love with you, Sam.
I always have been,
and it breaks my heart to
see you waste your affections
on Gary fucking King.
Hey, that's a bit harsh.
Oh, no, you've got
it all wrong.
There's nothing between...
And while I'm being honest,
just to lay it all out there,
I am currently seeing
a fitness instructor.
She's 26 years old,
but I would drop her in
a heartbeat if it meant
that I had one last chance
with you.
Steven, there's nothing
between me and Gary King.
(BOTH GRUNT)
Oh, fuck.
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Sorry.
Hey! Get your feet off her!
Pop its head off!
Pop its head off
like an aspirin bottle.
(SCREAMS)
Blue-bloods?
Nothing suggested in
the last three minutes
has been better than
Smashy-Smashy Egg Men.
Nothing.
What the hell's going on?
Did you guys think
of a name for the robots
who aren't robots?
I'm afraid we've
drawn a blank.
Well, we just had a barney
with two blanks
in the beer garden.
SAM: We have to leave now!
GARY: Agreed.
Let's hit The Mermaid.
Wait, what?
Number eight.
"Number eight"?
Oh, fuck.
Andy, what's happening?
Gary thinks we should keep
on with the crawl because
they know what we're doing,
but they don't know
that we know what
they're doing.
And basically no one else
has a better idea, so fuck it.
What?
Wait!
SAM: Guys! Guys!
I've got a better idea.
I'm parked right round
here somewhere.
Haul it. Just go!
Steven, tell them!
Gary said they'll get us
if we try and leave now.
We're way past leaving now.
Come on.
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHS)
Oh, yeah.
This is what the kids want.
This is a bit mad, isn't it?
This is perfect.
We can hide out in here.
I'll get the drinks in.
Good plan, O-Man.
Hey!
Keep an eye out
for blanks.
You've got it.
Why didn't you say anything?
About what?
About what you said
in the garden.
I always wanted to.
It just never seemed
like the right moment.
Something always
got in the way.
Here you go,
get these down you.
Thanks.
Steven?
Please! I have so
much to live for!
It's me, you numpty.
Basil!
I knew seeing your faces again
would spell trouble.
Wait. How do I know
it's really you?
Because I'm the only one
who's going to tell you the
truth about Newton Haven.
Now, do you recall the
events of the evening of
June the 22nd, 1990?
No, but I know a man who does.
Here you go.
Hey.
See anyone we know?
The Marmalade Sandwich.
They look good.
It's the lights.
It's the drink.
Who cares what it is?
SAM: Steven?
Steven?
That was the night
they arrived.
Remember the shooting star?
That was them.
Nothing happened at first.
They were getting ready,
burrowing in underground,
preparing.
Not long after you lot left,
people started to change.
Just one or two at first,
then more.
They replaced people
of influence, taking
over the institutions,
remaking, remodeling,
refurbishing.
Doing everything they could
to make us join them.
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
I can't find Steven.
Where are the others?
They're blending in.
Oh, crumbs.
It's not like the
replacements were
evil, far from it.
People got a lot friendlier.
That's how they do it.
It's not an invasion,
it's a merger.
They don't want to get
rid of us, not if they
can help it.
They just want to make
us more like them.
Change the way we think.
Bring us into line
with all the others.
Become another
link in their chain.
Which is fine,
unless you say no.
That's when you get replaced.
Once they get your DNA,
they've got you.
How do they do that?
BASIL: Any way they like.
Blood tests, the nit nurse,
sweat, kissing, saliva on
the rim of a glass.
Why do you think
I drink with this crazy straw?
Not so crazy now, is it?
If you're not on their side,
they'll create a version
that is.
They can bring you back
exactly the same or even
make you young again.
It looks like you,
it even has your
memories,
but really it's just a vessel
to spread their message.
Trust, love, respect, desire.
Replaced in the name
of progress.
So, what happens
to the people who
get replaced?
The empties?
Don't ask me what
happens to them.
Why, what happens
to the empties?
I told you not
to ask me that!
Go! Get out,
before it's too late!
Basil?
I said go!
This just can't be good.
Sam, who was the boy that
you liked in sixth form?
Adrian?
Adrian Keane. Why?
He's over there.
Hey, Sam.
How's life?
Sam, we have to
get out of here!
We have to get out of here!
Where are the others?
They're blending in.
Oh, fuck!
Gary!
No, just one
more song.
Gary, she's a blank!
Don't be so judgmental.
Oh, for fuck...
Oh, yeah.
Come on.
Still got it.
Enough's enough.
Let's go.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
hold up. Hold up.
(CHUCKLES)
Where are you all going?
ALL: We're leaving.
Really? What happened?
Adrian Keane
was in that bar.
Prick.
I thought you liked
Adrian Keane.
Adrian Keane is dead.
Oh, God.
Adrian Keane died in
a motorbike accident in
Italy eight years ago.
Did he?
They must have
had his DNA on file.
That's how they were
able to replicate him.
They know how
to get to us, man.
They know everything.
They didn't know
Adrian was dead.
They knew enough to tempt us.
They knew these three would
fall for a bunch of girls
in school uniform.
Hey, who wouldn't?
Am I right?
Fuck, yeah.
STEVEN:
We've gotta get out of town,
we've gotta get beyond it
before it's too late.
OLIVER: Where are you
getting all this from?
STEVEN: Basil.
Mad Basil? He of
the Bermuda Rhombus
and the Aqua Nazis?
Another good name
for the band, Steve.
You're putting our lives
in the hands of a crazy
old man?
He's not crazy!
No, maybe he's not.
Or maybe he's a blank
trying to lure us to the
edge of town,
onto those dark country roads
where they can deal with us.
Yeah, we could end
up dead in a field.
I hate fields.
OLIVER:
Yes. My thoughts precisely.
Steven's right.
We should go.
No, we're going
to The Beehive.
Gary's plan is still
the best we have.
Wait a minute.
The 1990-model Oliver was out
of commission by this point
in the evening.
What are you saying?
I like the new you.
Huh.
Come on.
This is a mistake,
isn't it?
GARY: Hold up!
Just stick with me.
GARY: Andy, come on!
Here we go.
Pub number nine.
(LAUGHING)
Fuck yes!
That's the spirit, Pete!
Spirits! We should do chasers.
Who is this guy?
Come on. Andy!
It can't start without you.
You what?
We can't start without you.
Now then.
Whose round is it?
It's mine.
Mr. Shepherd!
Is it Mr. Shepherd?
Why don't you kids join me?
You look like you could
do with a drink.
Now, let's have a little chat
about your future, shall we,
hmm?
Uh, Mr. Shepherd?
Please, call me Guy.
All right.
Guy...
(BOTH SNIGGER)
Look at you.
Are you a robot?
Does anyone know
what robot means?
Yeah. I do!
Yes, Gary.
It means "slave."
Oh, very good, Gary.
Are you a robot, sir?
No, Peter, of course
I'm not a robot.
Sir?
Yes, Steven.
But you're on their
side, though?
This is not about
sides, Steven.
It's not about shirts
versus skins.
It's about working
together as one team.
I know it may seem a bit weird
and a little bit scary,
but please believe me,
it's quite the opposite.
They're here to help.
To straighten us out.
To prepare us
for the big league.
They've seen something
in us, a potential.
There's a vast community
of worlds up there,
living together, peacefully,
cooperatively.
And guess what?
They want us along
for the ride.
Pretty cool, eh, gang?
(LAUGHING)
So, (CLEARS THROAT)
they're not here to harm us?
Far from it, O-Man.
No, they're here to help.
I'm not saying they're
afraid to get tough.
I certainly had to get
tough with you in my day.
And what one amongst you
wouldn't thank me for it? Hmm?
In some respects,
they're a lot like teachers.
Stern, yes.
A little frightening.
But it's all for
our betterment.
So, what do you say
we all go somewhere and
talk about this properly?
That wasn't properly?
Well, I think it's pretty
clear, guys, what Mr. Shepherd
is trying to say is that...
(ALL GASP)
Andy! What the fuck?
Yes, Andy. What the fuck?
WTF?
(SCREAMS)
(ALARMS RINGING)
Humans, you leave
us no recourse.
If you will not
join us willingly,
we will be forced to use
other means of persuasion.
Now, please...
(SCREAMS)
I fucking hate this town!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
Oh, oh!
Oh, crumbs,
you're heavy.
Sorry.
Motherfucker!
(EXCLAIMS)
Andy!
Twist the melon, man!
Yeah!
(GRUNTS)
Sam, this is no way
for a family to behave.
Sam, I'm disappointed
in you.
O-Man!
(GRUNTING)
Okay, Andy.
Break it up.
It doesn't have
to be like this.
It could be so much simpler,
so completely painless.
If only you'd see the light.
OLIVER: Yes.
See, it's not
about conflict,
it's about togetherness.
Yes. Let's try this
again, shall we?
How about another round?
Nah, we're done here.
Yes, Gary, that appears
to be the case. (SNAPS)
(ALARM RINGING)
The Smokehouse!
What?
Just do it!
Come on!
This way!
BOTH: Humans,
this is your final warning.
Failure to comply
will result in your...
(GASPS)
Humans, obey now,
or face the consequences.
Let's go!
(GRUNTING)
Shit.
Oh, look, there's my car!
Let's climb down
the drainpipe.
I've got a better idea.
(CAR ALARM WAILING)
Climb down the drainpipe.
Okay, just go.
Wait. What about the others?
Leave 'em with me, okay?
I got this.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I always
land on my feet.
I don't know
if that's true, Gary.
Just go.
Will you find out
what happened to
my brother?
Yeah, of course, of course,
and I'll look after Stevie
for you, eh?
He's a good guy.
He's better than me.
Gary, you're not a bad person,
but you're not boyfriend
material.
The whole "free spirit quick
one in the disabled toilets"
thing
is kinda cool when you're 17,
but not when you're facing 40.
There comes a time when
you have to go forwards
and not backwards.
Maybe if I hadn't left you
behind that night, things
would all be different.
It's not all about
that night, Gary.
Isn't it?
It doesn't have to be.
We'll always have the
disableds, though, won't we?
Yeah. Yeah, we'll always
have the disableds.
(STARTS ENGINE)
Oh, no.
(GRUNTING)
STEVEN: Where's Sam?
I put her in her car.
You did what?
I just told her to leave.
You just sent away
the only one of us
sober enough to drive?
Yeah.
You just couldn't
stand the fact
that she might
prefer me to you.
That's not true.
It is true, Gary!
I was getting somewhere.
We held hands.
I was just trying to help!
You were trying to help
yourself, more like!
Jesus, I do something right
for a change and you fuckers
get on my case.
Wow, that's the first time
I've ever heard you admit
being wrong.
I said I did something right!
Yeah, "for a change".
GARY: So?
Meaning the rest of
the time you're wrong.
Not necessarily.
Look, I just thought
it was best to keep her
out of harm's way.
And what about us, Gary?
Aren't we in harm's way?
We're all right, Pete.
Come on, we're
The Five Musketeers.
No, we're the Four Musketeers.
Wait, how do we know
you put her in the car?
How do we know
you're you?
Of course I'm me!
Well, who the fuck
are you, Gary?
I'm Gary King.
There's only one Gary King.
How do I know you guys
are you?
We've been together
the whole time.
You might all not be you.
How did you know O-Man
wasn't O-Man?
Because his birthmark
was back.
GARY: What does that prove?
Because of what Basil said.
They make a copy
from your DNA.
That's why he had
his birthmark.
He was new, like a baby.
Like a man-baby.
Like a "maybe".
Oliver with none of the shit
that had happened to the
real Oliver.
ANDY: The laser surgery!
So the blanks really
are just blank?
No wear and tear, no scars.
Steven, in 1987 we were
playing cricket and I
accidentally pushed you
onto a broken bottle that
nearly went up your ass.
So?
Show us your bum.
Very nice.
Thank you.
Pete, you got that 50cc
Suzuki in 1988,
and you let me have a go on it
and I ran over your leg.
What the fuck?
Oh, wait,
it's the other one.
(CHUCKLES)
Andy, in 1986 we re-enacted
the Knife Game from Aliens
and I stabbed you
in the middle finger.
How about December 1997,
when you OD'd
and I drove you
to the hospital
four times over the limit
and I ended up rolling the car
and almost severing
my femoral artery,
at which point you made
a miraculous fucking recovery
and ran off into the night,
leaving me to get arrested
after 12 hours of
life-saving surgery?
Either one of those will do.
Thank you.
What about you?
That's easy.
That could have
been drawn on.
Aren't all tattoos drawn on?
Yeah.
ANDY: Show us your arm.
What?
Show us your arm.
No, no.
You fell off stage at the
fifth-year ball fucking around
and dislocated your elbow.
You've got a scar
where they put the
metal plate in.
I don't have to show
you anything, all right?
I'm Gary King.
I know I'm me.
If I'm not me, then how do I
know that carved into
that beam above your head
are the words "King Gary"?
But it doesn't say
"King Gary".
Yes, it does.
Doesn't it?
No. It says "King Gay".
Some cunt scrubbed
out the "R"!
That was me.
GARY: Why?
"King Gay". (LAUGHS)
That means fuck-all anyway.
Mr. Shepherd remembered
stuff, so did Oliver.
Selective memory,
remember?
We don't see you for years
and you just pitch up
and bring us here.
You better come out
with some hard evidence
that you're human,
otherwise we're going to
find out for ourselves.
You want evidence?
There!
That proves I'm human!
It proves you're stupid.
Exactly!
Ow!
ALL: It's Gary.
It's Gary.
ANDY: The whole town's
out looking for us.
That's a good thing.
If everybody's outside,
that means nobody's inside.
Gary, wait! Fuck!
(LAUGHING)
ANDY: Gary, Gary!
What do you mean
"nobody's inside"?
I mean we can
still do this!
STEVEN: Do what exactly?
Oh, we're still on the crawl.
(LAUGHING)
"King Gay".
Peter?
Peter.
I thought that was you.
Are you okay?
Am I what?
I know we didn't see
eye to eye at school.
Goodness knows
I regret that.
I wanted to say something
back at the pub,
but I felt so terribly
ashamed by what I'd done.
Let me make it
up to you, Peter.
Please.
Gary, you're out
of your mind!
We've come too far.
It's fucking suicide.
I know. We are going to
get to The World's End
if it kills us.
Where's Pete?
PETER: I hate you!
You fucking bastard!
I hate you!
Pete! Leave it!
Why are you
doing this, Peter?
We don't want to hurt you.
Come on, mate!
It's not worth it!
Yes, it fucking is!
(SCREAMS)
What's he doing?
Oh, shit.
Peter...
I must say,
I'm very disappointed
in you, Peter.
I'll punch their
fucking lights out.
Andy! No, no, no,
there's too many of them.
Pete.
Peter.
We gotta go.
Gary's right.
We gotta get to
The King's Head.
Exactly.
What?
(GRUNTS)
We are not going
to The King's Head.
We're done.
We're going to do
what we should have
done in the first place.
Get The Beast and
get out of here.
We are fucking leaving
and we are never coming back.
Now, you can either
come with us willingly
or I'm gonna knock you
the fuck out and
carry you there myself.
You choose.
All right. All right.
Just think about what you're
saying, you know, because
you have been drinking.
You fuck.
STEVEN: Shit,
it's those fucking kids.
Not them again.
What the hell is that?
I don't know,
but it's definitely
not modern art.
Oh, shit, we're trapped.
Where's The Beast?
Okay, all right.
We're here, so The Beast
is in the next street.
How are we gonna
get to it?
We'll have to go through.
Through where?
I don't fucking
believe this.
Number 10.
Come on.
(GRUNTS)
Let's go.
The back door, back door.
Here we go.
Okay, there it is.
Shit.
We wait for an opening,
and then we leg it to
The Beast.
We need the keys.
ANDY: Gary?
Gary, what are you doing?
Just a little toast.
Gary, put the
pint down, yeah?
To Oliver, Pete.
And to us.
You know, 'cause
10 pubs isn't bad.
It's not, but
we're calling time.
Okay.
(SIGHS)
So close.
Number 10.
Okay.
So close.
No, no, no, no,
no. Gary!
Gary! Gary!
Let him go.
He left you, man.
I can't.
Andy!
Gary! Gary!
Gary, come back!
Come back, you
stupid bastard!
Gary!
Gary! Gary!
(GRUNTING)
Andy, look out!
Come on!
What the...
STEVEN: Get in. Get in.
Gary, Andy, get the fuck in!
You heard him, Andy.
Get the fuck in.
We haven't much time!
Andy! Go, now!
Steven!
Go!
(GRUNTS)
Andy.
I want you inside me.
Okay.
Cheers.
(OPENS DOOR)
(PANTING)
Ah!
You've had enough!
This is The World's End, man!
I know!
Stop this!
Leave me alone!
What do you care anyway?
Of course I fucking care.
There's a reason
I'm angry at you!
I know why you're angry
at me, okay?
But it's not my fault
that you crashed that car.
That's not the point.
You let me down, man.
You were Gary King.
Gary fucking King.
I would have followed
you to the end. (CHUCKLES)
I fucking have!
Then stop following me!
(GRUNTS)
No! It's just one more.
Let me have this.
You've got everything
you want.
What are you talking about?
You've got your perfect job
and your perfect house
and your perfect wife.
You think it's so perfect?
She left me, Gary.
She took the kids
to her mum's
three weeks ago.
Said I'm not present enough.
I'm trying to win her back.
And God knows
I am losing.
But I will continue to fight,
because that is
how we survive.
For fuck's sake, Gary,
I just punched my wedding
ring out of a robot's tummy.
Exactly!
You fight for
what's important.
But what is so important
about The Golden Mile?
It's all I've got!
Gary.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
You need help, Gary.
I got help.
You know what help was?
Help was a lot of people
sitting in a circle
talking about
how fucking awful
things had got.
That is not my idea
of a good time.
And this is?
They told me
when to go to bed.
Me!
Gary, mate, how can you
tell when you're drunk
if you're never sober?
I don't wanna be sober.
It never got better
than that night.
That was supposed to be
the beginning of my life.
All that promise
and fucking optimism.
That feeling like we
could take on the whole
universe.
It was a big lie.
Nothing happened.
You don't need
to do this, Gary.
Yeah, I do.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Please, stand by.
Ah!
What are you doing?
No, don't go out there.
THE LIGHT: Gary King.
Yeah?
Gary King of the humans.
Yeah. What do you want?
We are here to enable
your full potential,
as we have with countless
worlds across the galaxy.
Oh, yeah?
How'd you manage that, then?
We appropriate a small
percentage of the population
at 2,000 or so penetration
points across the planet.
This ensures maximum coverage.
From there, we create
simulants to spread
our ideologies
through peaceful
indoctrination.
Our objective is simple,
to ready the population
for participation in
our galactic community.
This method requires
a small sacrifice.
But the fewer
replacements we make,
the more successful
we consider our operation.
Of course, we welcome those
who volunteer themselves.
We can offer attractive
incentives for those
who willingly combine.
The chance to be young again
and yet retain selected
memories.
Isn't that something
you'd like?
Something you've
always wanted?
(GASPS)
Oh, my God! I'm so cute!
The beauty of our system
is that we all win.
There are no losers.
Allow me to carry
your legend forward.
Let the man you have become
be the boy you were.
(CHUCKLES)
Nah. (GRUNTS)
There's only one Gary King.
Then you have
made your choice,
Gary King of the humans.
Yeah, I have.
Because frankly, who the fuck
are you to come down here
and tell us what to do?
We are The Network
and we are here for
your betterment.
In the last 23 years,
have you not marveled as
information technology
has surged forward?
No.
Earth has grown smaller
yet greater as connectivity
has grown.
This is our doing and it
is just the beginning.
Oh, fuck off, you big lamp.
You are children
and you require guidance.
There is no room
for imperfection.
Hey, Earth
isn't perfect, all right?
And humans aren't perfect.
And guess what?
I ain't perfect.
And therein lies the necessity
for this intervention.
Must the galaxy be subjected
to an entire planet of people
like you?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Who put you in charge, huh?
Who are you to
criticize anyone?
Now, you might think
Gary's a bit of a cock,
and he is a bit of a cock,
but he's my cock.
Oh, thanks, man.
But he is a detriment to
himself, just as Earth is
a detriment to the galaxy.
What did you say?
You act out the same cycles
of self-destruction again
and again.
At this point your planet
is the least civilized
in the entire galaxy.
What did he say?
He's saying we're
a bunch of fuck-ups.
Hey, it's our
basic human right
to be fuck-ups.
This civilization
was founded on fuck-ups.
And you know what?
That makes me proud.
And me!
What is it they say?
"To err is..."
"To err is human."
"To err is human," so, uh...
We do not believe
you speak for all
humanity.
You are but two men.
Two drunk men.
STEVEN: Three drunk men!
BOTH: Stevie-baby!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Enough! Enough, humans!
Oh, you are in trouble now.
It's only the fucking
Three Musketeers.
You are revolting against
the wisdom of countless
solar systems.
Yeah, we are revolting!
You just said you're
not here to conquer.
Can I just ask,
how many people
did you have to replace
in Newton Haven?
That is irrelevant.
Is it?
Hands up.
Who here is human?
I'm human.
One!
And me.
That's two.
I am.
But don't know
for how long.
ALL: Basil!
Shh...
So what's that? Three?
You had to replace
an entire town?
Not the entire town.
Everybody apart
from old Nutbowl
and the Shifty twins.
That's a good name
for a band, Gary.
You should write that down.
I will.
What about the ones
you replaced,
like Peter and Oliver?
Yeah, what happened
to the empties?
BASIL: I told you
not to ask that!
Redundant vessels are
recycled, mulched and
converted into fertilizer,
whereupon they are returned
to the earth to promote
verdancy and growth.
It is a highly efficient
means of organic renewal.
Mulched?
It is a relative few
in light of our
long-term plan.
You mean a few hundred
thousand turned to fucking
compost?
What about the other places?
The penetration points.
(WHISTLES)
(BOTH GIGGLE)
Are they as successful
as Newton Haven?
Because I'm guessing
we're not the only
glitch in your system.
It is true, The Network
has been experiencing
some difficulties.
I think you bit off more
than you can chew
with Earth, mate.
Yeah, 'cause we
are more belligerent,
more stubborn
and more idiotic
than you can possibly imagine,
and I am not just
talking about Gary.
Yeah, there's more
than one Gary King.
But you said...
I fucking know
what I fucking said!
Your reliance on profanity is
a measure of your immaturity
as a man and a species.
Why don't you just get in your
rocket and fuck off back to
Legoland, you cunts!
Yeah! Stop fucking
Starbucking us, man!
Yeah!
It is our duty
to challenge you.
Just leave us to our own
devices, you intergalactic
arseholes.
You misunderstand.
Shut up!
We are trying...
Nobody's listening!
If you'd only...
Face it, we are the human race
and we don't like being told
what to do.
Just what is it
that you want to do?
We want to be free!
Yeah.
We want to be free to
do what we want to do!
Yeah.
We want to get loaded.
And we want to
have a good time.
And that's what
we're going to do.
It is pointless
arguing with you.
You will be left to
your own devices.
Really?
Yeah.
Fuck it.
They fucked off.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Up yours! Up yours! Up yours!
Yeah, we did it!
We won, we won!
(LAUGHING)
Gary, let's Boo-Boo.
Yeah, it's shit here,
innit?
Oi, up here!
Go!
Get up.
Come on!
Well done.
Thanks a bunch.
Had to go and spoil it,
didn't you?
Yeah, happy now?
Basil, what do we do now?
Same as before.
Go!
Where's The Beast?
The Beast is dead,
mate.
You know what...
You know what's
really annoying?
What?
I promised myself
I wouldn't die
in this town.
You're not gonna.
I think our luck just changed.
(HORN HONKING)
Whoo-hoo!
Oh!
SAM: Sorry!
Sam?
Yes.
You came back for us!
Yes, I did.
Well, I got lost on the
ring road. But, yes.
Hi, Sam, could you
give us a lift to London,
please?
Did you find out what
happened to my brother?
We'll tell you on the way.
Sorry about the mess.
I've been meaning to
clear that up.
We forgive you. Let's go.
Which way?
Backwards!
Which way now?
Go straight over!
(ALL SCREAMING)
We can make it.
We're gonna make it.
We made it!
(ALL COUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
I'm sorry.
I know.
ANDY: Everyone remembers
where they were
when the lights went out
on Planet Earth.
Me, Gary, Steven and Sam,
we were standing right
by the switch.
I guess it was
a big night for everyone.
That morning gave a whole
new meaning to the word
"hangover".
We decided to walk it off,
all the way back to London,
but the headache
didn't end there.
It just went on and on.
Talk about the Big Smoke.
When The Network went down,
it triggered some kind
of pulse,
wiped out all our technology
and sent us here,
back to the Dark Ages.
There were
casualties, of course.
I knew a few of them.
Some guy from work,
my cousin Paul,
Gary's mum.
Nobody really knew
how many we lost,
because we never heard from
the rest of the world again.
Everyone got cut off.
It isn't easy now,
but it is simpler.
I'm back with the wife,
which is something.
We decided our problems
didn't seem as bad in the
grand scheme of things.
We all had to go organic
in a big way,
but if I'm honest,
I'm hard pressed to recall
any processed foods
I actually miss.
As for the blanks,
well, a funny thing
happened there.
They woke up.
A week or so after The Network
pulled out, they just sort
of rebooted by themselves,
tried to start afresh.
They seemed lost at first,
children cut off
from their parents,
abandoned, forgotten,
looking for guidance, for
someone to show them the way.
I felt a bit sorry for them,
to be honest.
The Network was right
about one thing.
We can be a bit uncivilized.
Maybe we would've
been a bad influence
on the rest of the galaxy.
Oliver went back to
being an estate agent.
People still need a roof
over their heads,
and the old Ollie always
had a gift for the gab.
I guess the new one has, too.
(CHUCKLES)
He's doing all right.
I hear that the Peter
found his way home to
Bishop's Gardens.
I suppose he picked up
where the other one left off.
I'm not sure his wife noticed.
Maybe she chose not to.
He's a pretty good dad
by all accounts.
Steven and Sam got
together in the end.
Didn't see that coming.
They shacked up
just outside London.
It's a pretty nice shack, too.
As for Gary?
I don't know
what happened to Gary.
We got separated and
I never saw him again.
Some say he went
back to Newton Haven.
I don't know why.
I think his business
there was done.
It's funny,
but I miss him.
I wonder if he misses me.
Misses the boys.
Wherever he is,
I hope he's happy.
That's all he ever wanted,
really.
To have a good time.
I just hope he found it
beyond the bottom of a glass.
Because real happiness,
real friends, those are
things worth living for,
worth fighting for.
Blank bastards.
Fucking robots.
Five waters, please.
You can have one.
But I ain't serving this scum.
Well, I'm afraid it's all
for one and one for all.
You see, my young friends
and I are on an adventure.
A quest, if you will.
And since we find ourselves
in need of refreshment,
you, sir, have the honor
of drawing first blood.
So, I'll ask you again,
for the last time,
five waters, please.
Who the hell
do you think you are?
Me? They call me The King.
(SCREAMS)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)